# Mikiko Bazeley

San Francisco, CA | mmbazel@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/mikikobazeley | github.com/MMBazel

## **SUMMARY**

Machine Learning Engineer with 5+ years shipping data-driven solutions for high-growth companies in a variety of industries (solar, construction, recruitment-tech, & health-tech). Focused on full-cycle product engineering, including data engineering, ML model development, deployment, serving, monitoring & evaluation. Speaker, consultant, & mentor for initiatives & organizations focused on increasing representation in data science & machine learning.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## SIDEWALK.AI - San Francisco, CA

# Machine Learning Engineer

May 2019 - Present

Summary: First MLE at early-stage start-up focused on building Al-first enablement tools for residential real-state.

- Developed ML roadmap, research & implemented proof-of-concept models from papers (in listing recommendations, user profile clustering) utilizing Python (Scikit-learn, Surprise, Dask, GeoPandas), AWS RDS, Jupyter
- Developed early iteration of ETL pipelines using Python (including SQLAlchemy, paramiko, Dask) with logging, data cataloguing, & job status tracking for processing 1000+ text files (up to 8MB in size)
- Designed data models & schema, created DDL & DML scripts for Postgres (then Amazon RDS)
- Researched, documented, & acquired external datasets through scraping (Python Requests, BeautifulSoup, Scrapy) as well
  as through APIs (Quandl, Kaggle, etc)

#### TELADOC - Mountain View, CA

# Data Scientist II, Growth Marketing

Oct 2019 - Nov 2020

**Summary:** Collaborate closely with senior management to increase enrollment, activation & retention for members living with chronic & behavioral conditions (Diabetes, Hypertension, Pre-Diabetes, Weight Management).

- Provided experimentation support: Designed, set-up, & analyzed experiment results, including A/B tests (Python, Seaborn, SciPy, statsmodels, Metabase, SQLAlchemy)
- Lead projects in developing, documenting, scripting, & visualizing key metrics & analyses around marketing & growth
- Developed machine learning models (classification, regression, time series) & pipelines using Python (Pandas, Scikit-learn, Prophet, statsmodels), Redshift, S3. Leverage Metabase, Tableau & TabPy to engage stakeholders with analyses & machine learning model outputs around forecasting & prediction

#### WALKME - San Francisco, CA

# Sr Bl Analyst, Sales & Revenue Ops

Aug 2018 - Oct 2019

**Summary:** Responsible for leading & executing advanced analytics & data science initiatives for the revenue operations organization. Worked with key stakeholders to scope, develop, & present ML models.

- Developed sales & marketing pipeline demand model to set sales targets, evaluate pipeline funding options, & monitor key
  metrics (lead generation, lead coverage, opportunity conversion). Leveraged Python, Google sheets, Redshift, Tableau.
   Made strategic recommendations using model results to prevent potential risk of \$4M+ global revenue target miss.
- Developed pipeline allocation model & pipeline (with Python, Numpy) allocating lead generation targets from Demand Model to teams & individuals based on quota, start date & quota ramp. Model output ingested into external BI tool & CRM (Clari, Tableau) for real-time tracking of sales & actionable insight into opportunity velocity, leading to improvements in sales forecasting.
- Created propensity-to-purchase model using Salesforce data (opportunity, lead, & call records) as well as Python (simple-salesforce, NLTK, Spacy, Scikit-learn). Using features created around lead job titles, prospect account pain points, & historic demo call data, developed random forest model to predict propensity-to-first-purchase of account. Provided model interpretability using pdpbox, SHAP, & Scikit-learn.

**Summary:** Sole data science asset focused on understanding & driving user adoption of core products of construction software portfolio.

• Created customer scoring model in R utilizing account demographics, subscription & product usage data to flag customers struggling with product adoption. Model outputs scheduled for upload to Salesforce & Domo via scheduler, RForcecom, etc. with status reports automatically emailed to account owners via mailR.

SUNRUN - San Francisco, CA

### Analyst, Strategic FP&A

Oct 2016 - Jul 2017

**Summary:** Finance analyst partnered with sales & supply chain organizations for largest residential solar company with special focus on analytics, S& OP planning & forecasting.

- Created core financial models in Anaplan used for forecasting sales, sensitivity analysis & planning (annual & quarterly). Collaborated cross-functionally with sales, supply chain, & senior leadership to cut planning time by 75% while improving data fidelity & visibility.
- Utilized time series & look-alike analysis to produce materials forecasts for sales & supply chain to decrease change orders & overstock by 25% as well as created volume guidance for new markets & products.

VARIOUS COMPANIES - SF Bay Area, CA

## Various Roles, Business Operations

Dec 2013 - Oct 2016

Summary: Held various roles for a number of early- to mid-stage start-ups in bizops growth, and customer service.

# ADDITIONAL - TEACHING, MEDIA, HONORS, COMPETITIONS

AMAZON SPONSORED: GHC2020 WOMEN IN BOOTCAMP- AnitaB.Org

Scholarship: https://bit.ly/20LNgju

Jun 2020

(NOT IRL) PRIDE SUMMIT- Lesbians Who Tech

Selected Speaker: https://bit.ly/3fgJY0d

Jun 2020

Description: Led 30min Ted talk for over 100+ attendees on data visualization topic, "Visualizing History with Python:

Reproducing WEB Du Bois' Paris Exposition Exhibit, 35 years".

CAREER PANEL: WOMEN IN DATA SCIENCE - General Assembly

Invited Speaker: https://bit.lv/2BOZL86

Apr 2020

**Description:** Two-hour panel that featured "women who are successfully navigating the tech industry and developing exceptional work while motivating change."

Competition Standings: Selected Competitor & Team Finals (MIT Covid Datathon), Top 8% [of 800 Teams] (WiDs GOSSIS 2020 Kaggle Competition)

Teaching: Data Science Mentor (Data Science Dream Job), Data Science & Analytics Mentor (Springboard)

#### **EDUCATION**

UNIVESITY OF CALIFORNIA, SAN DIEGO - La Jolla, CA

Economics & Anthropology, B.A.

2013

#### **SKILLS**

Languages: Python [scikit-learn, pandas, numpy, genism, spacy, OpenCV], SQL [Postgres, MySQL, Oracle], R, Java, C++ Applications: Databricks/PySpark, Docker, Kubernetes, Airflow, AWS [Athena, Redshift, RDS, S3, Sagemaker, Glue, Kinesis, CloudWatch], Streamlit, Flask

Certificates: Full Stack Deep Learning, Deep Learning Specialization (Coursera – deeplearning.ai), Supply Chain Management (Micromasters – MITx), Database Programming: MySQL (CCSF), Data Science Bootcamp (Springboard), Machine Learning Engineering (Springboard)